I am the granddaughter of the late Nobuko.
Oh, Ms. Nobuko.
Let me carry that.
Mr. Nishigami.
Mr. Nishigami!
See you tomorrow!
At the end of summer,
this villa ground will be hit
by a large-scale landslide
disaster due to a typhoon.
All that's left is to quietly wait
for death at the end of summer.
I think so too, but…
It is forbidden for a Grim Reaper
to feel affection for humans.
You must devote yourself entirely
to witnessing their lifespans.
Understood.
That is my mission, after all.
The Obon holidays started today,
and since this morning,
expressways across Japan
have been congested.
-This is one of those highways.
-Obon holidays, huh.
-The countryside and tourist spots…
-What do we do on Obon again?
Well, it's Obon, but we don't have
anything special to do, right?
Shouldn't we at least visit Midori's
grandma's grave? She built this villa.
What?
What are you saying?
Let's go swimming!
Are you going to the sea?
Yeah! Just earlier,
when I was passing by the beach,
there were hardly any people!
Gosh, that's hot.
-Let's go swimming!
-No way! We don't have our swimsuits!
It's fine! I'm going like this.
It will be fine. Let's go!
You were hiding it with the float…
Who might you be?
Focus!
That's right.
No one had been to this villa for years.
But I heard lots of young people
had been visiting it.
Our temple's supporters told me,
so I came to check things out.
We are the grandchildren of the owner
of this villa. We have the key!
Listen.
The Obon holiday
is not meant for drinking
and playing around.
For Japanese people,
Obon is an annual event,
where we light lanterns,
welcome the spirits
of ancestors back home,
and offer gratitude and memorial services.
It is a solemn and sacred Buddhist event.
Focus!
Nishigami, please teach them
about the various events of Obon.
Sir…
The remains that I left in your care,
are they still…
Oh, right.
Of course, they are safely kept.
About that…
Did the owner of this place
ask you to do that?
Yes.
I was asked to keep a portion
of her ashes near this villa
by the owner.
When were you asked to do that?
Right before she passed away,
or after she passed away?
Right.
She can't ask you after she died, huh.
Focus!
Oh, isn't it here? This looks likely.
This room looks like it has lanterns.
-Right.
-It's packed with so many things.
-Yeah.
-Oh, look, a candle.
You're right.
Come to think of it,
have we ever actually gone to visit
Grandma's grave?
Where would the grave even be?
We hadn't seen Grandma at all
after she remarried, right?
Huh? Did we go to Grandma's funeral?
Yeah, we did go. I sort of remember it.
Oh, could it have been held
at the funeral home here in Tatsumi Town?
I don't remember a single thing.
So, did you come here often
when you were kids?
I only came here once or twice
when I was in early elementary school.
Wait.
But for summer vacation,
we caught insects, right?
We did, right? Huh?
Konta. You remember
what happened yesterday, right?
Yesterday?
Oh, I…
-My memory might have been erased.
-The heck?
But won't you inherit this villa?
No!
This place belongs to my Grandma's
husband's family. They're rich.
-We are just borrowing the key.
-Yeah.
It's not a lantern, but I found a lamp.
Well, good enough, I guess.
Huh? What is this?
How nostalgic. A Hato Sablés box!
Oh, Hato Sablés!
-What about this lamp?
-What are you doing?
There's a notebook. A diary?
-Wow!
-Oh!
How cute.
Midori, did you draw manga?
-I used to love drawing when I was little.
-I see.
I might have drawn this here
during summer vacation.
Wow, this brings back memories.
I wonder if Grandma kept it for me.
You were actually quite good.
No doubt it's a shoujo manga!
-Right?
-I was copying the manga I liked.
But I had forgotten all about it.
Somehow, when you grow up,
you forget these kinds of things.
-Wait, they are kissing in this one!
-Oh, wow!
Oh, no!
-Grandma's photo!
-I want to see it!
She was a beauty.
Wasn't she way too beautiful?
-How nostalgic.
-She was stylish.
Right?
She's holding an orange.
You're right.
-Midori!
-What?
I found a yukata in the storage room.
So cute! It's so retro.
Try it on.
Must be a keepsake from your grandma.
-I'll help you put it on.
-Really?
Well, maybe I'll wear it then.
It won't split at all. One more try!
It won't split at all.
Is the angle the problem here?
Do I have to strike it at this angle?
-I can't do it.
-That's too weak! Stronger!
-It's scary, Konta!
-Put your back into it!
-Okay.
-Try it.
That's no good.
-Konta…
-Do it like, "Bam!"
Focus! Like that.
-I can't do it.
-You need to yell!
Mr. Nishigami.
Oh, Mr. Nishigami.
See, Tetsuro is totally terrible at it,
so go teach him.
-Yes.
-Okay.
-I can't do it at all.
-We need firewood for the send-off fire.
Ta-da!
Oh! So cute!
-Yay!
-So cute!
-Thank you.
-My sister is so cute.
-How is she so cute?
-Really, thanks.
From 5:00 p.m.,
the Tatsumi Town
Summer Festival will begin…
Summer festival?
-Please do come and enjoy.
-It's Obon, so maybe an Obon festival?
It's held around this time every year.
Really? I would like to go.
Where is it being held?
Shall I guide you?
Huh? Oh! Please do!
Let's all go together.
I don't want that monk
to yell at me again.
We'll stay here.
What?
Go and have fun!
Well, I'll go take a quick look.
-Have fun.
-Okay!
-I'm going too…
-No, not you.
-You've got to chop wood.
-What?
Hey, the two of them left together.
A festival, huh. We only have one yukata.
Yeah.
-All right, let's prepare for Obon!
-Yeah.
Let's set up the welcoming fire.
Yay.
Good, Tetsuro. Harder!
Yes, right on!
It was a small festival,
but it even had food stalls.
It was fun.
Next time,
I hope I can come with everyone.
There are many different events
during Obon, aren't there?
There sure are.
The Obon holidays
are the only time working adults
get to have a long summer holiday.
I'm glad I got to have
a Japanese-style vacation.
Ms. Midori.
Yes?
Shall we stop by one more place?
What?
MAIN GATE
Wow.
Please wait a moment.
Could this be…
My Grandma's?
Ms. Nobuko really loved this town.
Can I…
take this back with me?
Uh…
I think Grandma would be happier
if we kept them in the villa.
It's Obon, after all.
I will take them back.
Hold on.
It's been a while. Has it been a year?
-Your grandchild, I think he got married?
-That's right!
I can rest easy now.
GHOSTS
Mr. Nishigami.
It has been a year.
Mr. Nishigami,
thank you for the other day!
Let's go.
Did you get a girlfriend?
Mr. Nishigami.
-Mr. Nishigami.
-Come on!
I'm very sorry.
Oh, no, please don't apologize.
Oh, thank you very much.
This way
Grandma can return to the villa too.
I knew it.
These kinds of events
are important, aren't they?
From next year,
I'll be sure to give her
a much warmer welcome.
Next year…
-By Obon next year…
-Oh, dango!
For Obon,
we make offerings of dango, right?
Next year,
I will make dango for my Grandma.
But…
It's strange, isn't it?
When I was working in Tokyo,
I never paid Obon any mind.
Well, I only cared how many days
of Obon holiday I could get.
But…
Even when I got time off,
I would just be sleeping at home
or looking at my smartphone.
Since coming here,
I've realized that I was living
a rather bland life in Tokyo.
I know that now.
I was always tired,
and there was nothing I wanted to do.
-Is that so?
-Yeah.
Even my late grandma,
I hadn't seen her in years,
so I never really thought about her.
But, thanks to this villa,
thanks to this vacation,
I was able to get in touch
with my precious memories.
I found them again.
I'm glad I decided to take this vacation.
Is that so?
I'm glad I met you, Mr. Nishigami.
I'm home, Mr. Nishigami.
Grandma, welcome back.
It has been a while,
Mr. Nishigami.
At the end of summer,
a great typhoon will come,
and there will be a landslide.
Oh, dear!
Will they all die?
Let me talk with them!
There is nothing I can do.
You all must leave this place.
What's wrong?
Go back to Tokyo right now!
I may be falling in love
for the first time!
Subtitle translation by: Nix S.